Spain, Malaga (EU citizenship)

Mob: +34 659694955

Email: gunars.lazdans@gmail.com

Date of Birth: 10th May 1987

My personal website: <u>lazdans.com</u>

Gunars Lazdans

Profile

Enthusiastic guy with 10 years of experience in the IT industry. I started my IT carrier by working in the Quality Assurance specialty for 8 years, it all began with manual testing, but soon after that I started to get more and more exposure to test automation and by that, I started to increase my technical skills. Later down the line I was able to transition to a software development position and worked as a Frontend Engineer for 2 years.

During my career I have gained a lot of experience working in agile/scrum methodology on projects with complex architecture and millions of users, working closely with my team to deliver value to the production environment as soon as possible.

Education, certification and courses

- Udemy Course Certificate: Angular The Complete Guide (2022 Edition)
- Course: Java 1 Introduction to Java. (2017) JavaGuru.lv
- ISTQB® Certified Tester Foundation Level certification (2016)
- Riga Technical university (2008 2012)
 Bachelor's degree in Computer Science Computer systems design and software

Employment History

Frontend Engineer

The Workshop - Inventors of Play / Online Gambling industry Spain (Malaga) January 2020 – November 2021

- Work in an environment with complex software architecture
- Front-End development with Angular and TypeScript, tested with Jasmine, Karma and Cypress
- Delivering changes to production using Bamboo CI/CD pipelines
- Some Back-End tasks in Java with REST API Endpoint implementation
- Participation in the code review process

QA Engineer

The Workshop - Inventors of Play / Online Gambling industry Spain (Malaga) June 2018 – January 2020

- Test Automation using Selenium Web driver and Cypress.io
- Test planning for new features
- Participation in the code review process

Software Test Specialist

TELE2 SHARED SERVICE CENTRE / Telecommunication industry Latvia (Riga) October 2015 – January 2018

- Perform Sanity tests on integrated Siebel CRM system
- Use agile methodology on a daily basis within a team located in different geographic locations
- Development of automation scripts in an internal keyword-based automation framework
- Use SQL on a daily basis to interact with Oracle DBS to prepare or modify test data

Software Test specialist

SOAAR / Software development industry Latvia (Riga) September 2013 – October 2015

- Software testing
- User scenario management
- Web Application test automation
- Selenium Web driver tests development in Java

IT Specialist

RTU Riga Business School / Education field Latvia (Riga) January 2012 – August 2013

- IT / office equipment maintenance
- Computer laboratory administration
- Video conference administration

Tools and Software Applications

Industry Knowledge:

Agile, Scrum, Software Development Life Cycle, Data Modelling, Requirements Analysis

Tools & Technologies:

Angular, NgRx, RxJS, FireBase, React Native, Postman, Cypress.io, Selenium Web driver, Git, JIRA, WindowsOS, MacOS, MS Office, IntelliJ IDEA, Visual Studio Code

Languages:

TypeScript, JavaScript, SQL, NoSQL, HTML, CSS, Saas

Interpersonal Skills:

Teamwork, Mentoring, Presentation Skills

Driver's Licence

B Category

Language knowledge

- English Advanced
- Latvian Native
- Russian Intermediate
- Lithuanian Advanced
- Spanish Basic

Personal Interests